<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<CodeSystem xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="THREEMAPRDRG"/>
  <text>
    <status value="generated"/><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This code system http://terminology.hl7.org/temporary-uri/codeSystem/3M/APRDRG defines many codes, but they are not represented here</p></div>
  </text>
  <url value="http://terminology.hl7.org/temporary-uri/codeSystem/3M/APRDRG"/>
  <version value="0.1.10"/>
  <name value="THREEMAPRDRG"/>
  <title value="All Patient Refined Diagnosis Related Groups (APR-DRGs)"/>
  <status value="active"/>
  <date value="2020-11-11T14:40:52+00:00"/>
  <publisher value="HL7 Financial Management Working Group"/>
  <contact>
    <name value="HL7 Financial Management Working Group"/>
    <telecom>
      <system value="url"/>
      <value value="http://www.hl7.org/Special/committees/fm/index.cfm"/>
    </telecom>
    <telecom>
      <system value="email"/>
      <value value="fm@lists.HL7.org"/>
    </telecom>
  </contact>
  <description value="3M APR DRGs have become the standard across the U.S. for classifying hospital inpatients in non-Medicare populations. As of January 2019, 27 state Medicaid programs use 3M APR DRGs to pay hospitals, as do approximately a dozen commercial payers and Medicaid managed care organizations. Over 2,400 hospitals have licensed 3M APR DRGs to verify payment and analyze their internal operations.&#xA;&#xA;The 3M APR DRG methodology classifies hospital inpatients according to their reason for admission, severity of illness and risk of mortality.&#xA;&#xA;Each year 3M calculates and releases a set of statistics for each 3M APR DRG based on our analysis of large national data sets. These statistics include a relative weight for each 3M APR DRG. The relative weight reflects the average hospital resource use for a patient in that 3M APR DRG relative to the average hospital resource use of all inpatients. Please note that payers and other users of the 3M APR DRG methodology are responsible for ensuring that they use relative weights that are appropriate for their particular populations. The 3M APR DRG statistics also include data for each 3M APR DRG on relative frequency, average length of stay, average charges and incidence of mortality.&#xA;&#xA;3M APR DRGs can be rolled up into broader categories. The 326 base DRGs roll up into 25 major diagnostic categories (MDCs) plus a pre-MDC category. An example is MDC 04, Diseases and Disorders of the Respiratory System. As well, each 3M APR DRG is assigned to a service line that is consistent with the outpatient service lines that are defined by the 3M&#x2122; Enhanced Ambulatory Patient Groups (EAPGs).&#xA;&#xA;A link to information about the code system - including how to obtain the content from 3M is provided [here.](https://www.3m.com/3M/en_US/health-information-systems-us/drive-value-based-care/patient-classification-methodologies/apr-drgs/). Identifying a DRG code requires a version.&#xA;&#xA;_**Note: A temporary URL has been defined for this codesystem for use in draft implementation guides. It should be noted that the authoritative canonical URL will be different.**_"/>
  <jurisdiction>
    <coding>
      <system value="urn:iso:std:iso:3166"/>
      <code value="US"/>
    </coding>
  </jurisdiction>
  <copyright value="The clinical logic is maintained by a team of 3M clinicians, data analysts, nosologists, programmers and economists. The logic is proprietary to 3M but is available for licensees to view in an online definitions manual.&#xA;&#xA;To license APR-DRGs from 3M, see request form [here](https://engage.3m.com/PPS_Groupers_Contact)"/>
  <content value="not-present"/>
</CodeSystem>