<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<CodeSystem xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="ICD10CM"/>
  <text>
    <status value="generated"/><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This code system http://hl7.org/fhir/sid/icd-10-cm defines many codes, but they are not represented here</p></div>
  </text>
  <url value="http://hl7.org/fhir/sid/icd-10-cm"/>
  <version value="0.1.10"/>
  <name value="ICD10CM"/>
  <title value="International Classification of Diseases, Tenth Revision, Clinical Modification (ICD-10-CM)"/>
  <status value="active"/>
  <date value="2020-11-10T23:20:04+00:00"/>
  <publisher value="HL7 Financial Management Working Group"/>
  <contact>
    <name value="HL7 Financial Management Working Group"/>
    <telecom>
      <system value="url"/>
      <value value="http://www.hl7.org/Special/committees/fm/index.cfm"/>
    </telecom>
    <telecom>
      <system value="email"/>
      <value value="fm@lists.HL7.org"/>
    </telecom>
  </contact>
  <description value="The National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS), the Federal agency responsible for use of the International Statistical Classification of Diseases and Related Health Problems, 10th revision (ICD-10) in the United States, has developed a clinical modification of the classification for morbidity purposes. The ICD-10 is used to code and classify mortality data from death certificates, having replaced ICD-9 for this purpose as of January 1, 1999. ICD-10-CM is the replacement for ICD-9-CM, volumes 1 and 2, effective October 1, 2015.&#xA;&#xA;The clinical modification represents a significant improvement over ICD-9-CM and ICD-10. Specific improvements include: the addition of information relevant to ambulatory and managed care encounters; expanded injury codes; the creation of combination diagnosis/symptom codes to reduce the number of codes needed to fully describe a condition; the addition of sixth and seventh characters; incorporation of common 4th and 5th digit subclassifications; laterality; and greater specificity in code assignment. The new structure will allow further expansion than was possible with ICD-9-CM.&#xA;&#xA;Current and previous releases of ICD-10-CM are available in PDF and XML format here: [https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/icd/icd10cm.htm](https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/icd/icd10cm.htm)&#xA;&#xA;Most files are provided in compressed zip format for ease in downloading. These files have been created by the National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS), under authorization by the World Health Organization. Any questions regarding typographical or other errors noted on this release may be reported to nchsicd10cm@cdc.gov."/>
  <jurisdiction>
    <coding>
      <system value="urn:iso:std:iso:3166"/>
      <code value="US"/>
    </coding>
  </jurisdiction>
  <copyright value="The ICD-10 is copyrighted by the [World Health Organization (WHO)external icon](http://www.who.int/classifications/icd/en/), which owns and publishes the classification. WHO has authorized the development of an adaptation of ICD-10 for use in the United States for U.S. government purposes. As agreed, all modifications to the ICD-10 must conform to WHO conventions for the ICD. ICD-10-CM was developed following a thorough evaluation by a Technical Advisory Panel and extensive additional consultation with physician groups, clinical coders, and others to assure clinical accuracy and utility.&#xA;&#xA;The following requirements must be followed to utilize CDC&#x2019;s public domain content:&#xA;&#xA;1) Attribution to the agency that developed the material must be provided in your use of the materials. Such attribution should clearly state the materials were developed by CDC ATSDR and/or HHS (e.g., Source: CDC; Materials developed by CDC);&#xA;&#xA;2) You must utilize a disclaimer which clearly indicates that your use of the material, including any links to the materials on the CDC, ATSDR or HHS websites, does not imply endorsement by CDC, ATSDR, HHS or the United States Government of you, your company, product, facility, service or enterprise. All such disclaimers must be prominently and unambiguously displayed (e.g., Reference to specific commercial products, manufacturers, companies, or trademarks does not constitute its endorsement or recommendation by the U.S. Government, Department of Health and Human Services, or Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;&#xA;&#xA;3) You may not change the substantive content of the materials; and&#xA;&#xA;4) You must state that the material is otherwise available on the agency website for no charge.&#xA;&#xA;For information on NCHS agency level use of materials see [here](https://www.cdc.gov/other/agencymaterials.html)."/>
  <content value="not-present"/>
</CodeSystem>